Payal Priyadarshini

Mobile: 07549231832

Email: payal.priyadarshini@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Full Stack PHP Web Developer with rich experience and updated skills. Looking for a part time/flexible work environment with an opportunity to work in diverse projects. Experienced full stack ASP.NET developer in the past but with a gap of about 12 years. Worked in Microsoft technologies such as C#, SQL Server etc. Worked in an Agile environment, has good communication skills and team player. Seeking opportunities to again step into web development after a long parental leave.

SKILLS

Updated skills:

Languages: PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery

Database: MySQL

Tools: Adobe Illustrator, Adobe PhotoShop, GIMP, Adobe InDesign, NODEJS, GIT, GITHUB, Responsive

Web Design, Bootstrap, SASS, WordPress, IDE – WebStorm, Netbeans

Packages: WebPack, Browser-Sync, Gulp

Please find my portfolio at www.payalcreations.co.uk

Previously worked using the following:

Languages: C# (Visual Studio 2003/2005/2008/2010), J2SE (Eclipse), JavaScript, XML, HTML, CSS, Ajax

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server 2000/2005/2008, Data Transformation Service

Tools: NCover, NArrange, NUnit, Reporting Service & Crystal Reports, Visual SourceSafe,

CruiseControl.Net, SharePoint, ReSharper, Team Foundation Server, StyleCop, FxCop, Kentico CMS

Application Architecture: Design Patterns, Use cases & UML

Familiar with: LINQ to SQL, Entity Framework, MVC

EXPERIENCE

Website Administrator, Volunteering

11/2019 - Present

Cambourne Timebank www.cambournetimebank.org.uk, Cambourne

Volunteering as a Website Administrator for Cambourne Timebank. My responsibilities include to take care of all aspects of the websites, starting from deciding on the Web hosting service, setup the website from scratch on WordPress, making Logo for Cambourne Timebank, good look and feel of the website and keeping it up to date with all the latest and relevant information. I had also setup SSL for the website.

I also take opportunities in my social network, wherever possible to apply my skills, either by implementation or by providing guidance. Some of these being working for a charities: Assistance in setting up website for CERC (http://camcare.org.uk/cerc/), creation of poster for activities in HSS, consultancy and guidance for website setup of company in India , Prakash Sports (www.prakashsports.com)

Pursuing Web Designer Career Programme

Training Dragon, London

I have showcased my projects in my portfolio at: www.payalcreations.co.uk

This comprehensive course is targeted to refresh my skills in the following areas:

- 1. **HTML5, CSS3, basic JavaScript**: This course explained how to create web pages from scratch using different techniques, such as HTML5, CSS3, basic JavaScript using professional tools and workflow, as well as following high coding standards. The complete course is hands-on based.
- 2. **Graphic Design :** This course explained how to create designs for business card, logo, website and newsletter using softwares like Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Indesign and Adobe Illustrator.
- 3. **Javascript & JQuery**: This course explained how to use JavaScript to create interactive web pages, create JQuery effects and animations on your web pages.
- 4. **PHP & mySQL:** This course explains how to create dynamic websites. This course covered a range of topics such as building an ecommerce shop, creating a content management system (CMS), developing contact us forms, developing web forms and handling form data using PHP and SQL and lots more.
- 5. WordPress: Developing websites using WordPress.
- 6. **Advanced HTML5 & CSS3**: This course explains how to create interactive websites using advanced HTML5 & CSS3. This course covered a range of topics such as video support, HTML5 APIs, Canvas and SVG and HTML5 Forms.
- 7. **Responsive web design:** This course explains how to create mobile web pages.
- 8. **SQL:** This course covered a range of topics such as SQL Concepts, Database concepts, SELECT, CREATE, UPDATE and DELETE
- 9. Bootstrap: This course explains how to create responsive web pages using Bootstrap
- 10. **NODEJS TOOLS:** This course introduces Node.Js environment and build tools to improve modern Front-end workflow e.g. Node Package Manager(NPM), browser-sync, Webpack, Yarn, Grunt, Gulp
- 11. **GITHUB & GIT:** This Git and GitHub course explains how to use Version Control and Git as a Distributed Version Control System (DVCS)
- 12. SASS: This SASS course explains how to use get, install and use SASS preprocessor for projects.

Teaching Assistant 9/2016 – 4/2019

Morley Memorial Primary School, Cambridge.

Since my children were very young, I started looking for some opportunities that would fit well with work and home life balance and decided to pursue job of teaching assistant. I learnt soft skills like team work, discipline, communication, leadership and confidence. I prepared myself with a 'CACHE Level 3 Diploma in Supporting Teaching and Learning' from TA College and pursued the profession successfully here in UK.

Parental Leave - 2010 - 2016

Senior Programmer at ICT Embedded B.V. (now The ICT Group)

2/2008 – 7/2009

Project - Raet Payroll Direct: Team size –10. Raet Payroll Direct was the online solution for salary
processing for the business community. This application used the Software As A Service (SaaS)
technology.

- Converted the application from old WebFocus to ASP.NET. Worked on both front end & back end structure, prepared user documentation, coaching & giving presentations within the team.
- Project HREasy: Team size –10. Raet HR Easy was the online solution for personnel administration
 within organizations concentrating mainly on administrative and operational tasks. This application
 used the old ASP/SaaS technology.
 - Converted the old application built in ASP to ASP.NET, developing Reports Reporting services, Report Viewer, managed front end structure – C#. Worked with Master Pages, Web Parts, MultiView and Reflection etc, introduced Agile in the team.
- Project-Journalisation: Team size –3. This application used the old WebFocus/SaaS technology.
 - Managed back end structure, writing test cases for unit tests and testing them with NUnit.

Software Developer at Drie-O Automatisering B.V.

4/2006 - 6/2007

- Project Siriusweb, Rabobank Eindhoven: Team size 6. Siriusweb was a workflow management system for Rabobank.
 - Worked on the change-requests for workflow management system, customer information & edossier document, worked with all GUI, business logic and database related issues.
- Project Hobij (hobij.nl): Team size 5. Hobij is an employment agency.
 - Provided implementation (CRUD on SQL Server 2000) using XML and merge fields, Implemented the Job and Candidate part of the web application (C#).
- Standard product for housing agency: Team size 3.
 - Built a housing agency buildings management system (C#) from scratch to end (Full life cycle development) with different login and roles, electronic dossier for different logins, developed reports using crystal reports for an overview of the buildings and rooms etc.

Language Instructor at Tata Infotech,

 Worked as a faculty member for teaching C, C++ and Java 	7/2003 – 5/2005
EDUCATION	
B.Tech. Electronics and Telecommunications	1998 - 2002
North Maharashtra University, Jalgaon, India	
Indian School Certificate (Year 12)	1998
Indian Certificate of Secondary Education	1995

TRAININGS AND CERTIFICATIONS (Before parental leave)

M2734: Updating your Database Development skills to Microsoft SQL Server 2005, Atricon information Services.

- FJ-310: Developing Applications for the Java EE Platform, Sun Microsystems.
- SL-425: Architecting and Designing J2EE Applications, Sun Microsystems.
- 70-315: Developing and implementing Web applications with Visual C#.NET and Visual Studio.NET 2003.
- 70-528: TS Microsoft .NET Framework 2.0 Web Based Client Development.